[{"niche":"home loans","question":"What does 'LMI' stand for?","answers":["Lenders Mortgage Insurance.","Loan Monthly Insurance.","Lenders Monthly Interest.","Loan monthly interest."]},{"niche":"home loans","question":"Exit fees' are also known as...?","answers":["Early repayment fees.","Withdraw fee.","Default fee.","Re-financing fee."]},{"niche":"home loans","question":"What is a redraw facility?","answers":["A feautre that allows you to withdraw additional payments that you have already put towards your loan.","A competitive interest rate on your loan.","A repayment shedule for a loan.","The monthly repayment fee."]},{"niche":"home loans","question":"What is an ongoing fee?","answers":["Monthly or annual fees charged by the lender.","An ad-hoc fee.","An occasional fee charged with greater interest.","A fortnightly fee charged by the lender to maintain the loan account."]},{"niche":"home loans","question":"Who is a guarantor?","answers":["Someone who assumes responsibility for a portion of your loan.","The lender's account manager.","A financial advisor.","A mortgage broker."]},{"niche":"home loans","question":"What does 'FHOG' stand for?","answers":["First Home Buyers Grant.","First Home Bidding Grant.","First Home Buyer's Guide.","First Home Bidder's Guide."]},{"niche":"home loans","question":"An application fee is...","answers":["The fee charged by a lender when you lodge a loan application.","A fee charged throughout the course of your loan.","The accured interest fee on your loan.","Capital gains tax fee."]},{"niche":"home loans","question":"Why are lenders required to display the comparison rate of a loan?","answers":["To reflect the true cost of a loan.","To mislead consumers.","To clearly demonstrate the features of a loan.","To clearly reflect the accured interest on the loan."]},{"niche":"home loans","question":"Capital gain is...","answers":["The amount by which proceeds from the sale of a property exceeds the original purchase price.","The loss made from a sale of an investment property.","The accrued interest made on a property.","The variable interest that is taxable on a loan."]},{"niche":"home loans","question":"If someone 'defaults' on a loan, what does it mean?","answers":["They fail to make payment on the due date.","They continue to make repayments on the loan.","They take out a personal loan.","They evaluate the cost of their loan."]},{"niche":"home loans","question":"Which of these banks currently offer a capped rate home loan?","answers":["Holiday Coast Credit Union","Commonwealth Bank","People's Choice Credit Union","ANZ"]},{"niche":"home loans","question":"Applying for a home loan will result in what action happening to your credit file?","answers":["A credit enquiry will be listed on it","A default will be listed on it","Nothing","Your credit file will be sent to the central banking authority in Rand McNally"]},{"niche":"home loans","question":"Which of these fees is not included in a comparison rate?","answers":["Your Solicitor's fees","Annual fees","Application fees","Monthly fees"]},{"niche":"home loans","question":"Which of these organisations offer home loans in Australia?","answers":["Dnister","Deustche Bank","Commsec","UBS"]},{"niche":"home loans","question":"How can you borrow 100% of a property's value in Australia?","answers":["With a guarantor","With a 100% home loan","With a letter from your accountant","By baking your banker a cake"]},{"niche":"home loans","question":"The usual example of a comparison rate for home loans in Australia is based on:","answers":["A loan of $150,000 over 25 years.","A loan of $125,000 over 30 years.","A loan of $175,000 over 25 years.","A loan of $500,000 over 30 years."]},{"niche":"home loans","question":"Most lenders don't want to see your monthly repayments exceed what percentage of your gross monthly income?","answers":["30%","50%","15%","75%"]},{"niche":"home loans","question":"How is capital gains tax on the sale of a property paid?","answers":["Through your income tax for the financial year of the sale","Online through the ATO website","At your relevant Office of State Revenue ","At the local servo"]},{"niche":"home loans","question":"RAMS is owned by which Australian bank?","answers":["Westpac","NAB","Commonwealth bank","Bankwest"]},{"niche":"home loans","question":"Which Australian actor starred in a series of Bank of Melbourne TV ads in the 80s/90s?","answers":["Jack Thompson","David Hasselhoff","Ray Meagher","Cher"]},{"niche":"personal loans","question":"What is an overdraft?","answers":["A line of credit linked to your transaction account.","A type of product that lets you increase a loan you've already taken out. ","An emergency line of credit attached to your home loan.","A situation where you are given too much money by the bank and are required to repay it. "]},{"niche":"personal loans","question":"Do you get charged interest on a payday loan?","answers":["No â€“ the fees are representated as interest. ","Yes, the interest is very high.","You get charged fees and interest.","You don't get charged interest or fees. "]},{"niche":"personal loans","question":"What are the two fees you get charged with a payday loan?","answers":["Eastablishment fee and monthly fee. ","Establishment fee and weekly fee","A loan startup fee and a daily fee","An annual fee and a loan administration charge"]},{"niche":"personal loans","question":"What kind of loan can you use to buy a car?","answers":["Any type of personal loan.","A secured personal loan or a car loan.","A car loan","A secured personal loan. "]},{"niche":"personal loans","question":"What is considered a 'small amount loan' by ASIC and therefore has a cap on the interest and fees that can be charged?","answers":["Loans of under $2,000 that are repaid between 16 days and 1 year","Loans of of between $1,000 and $2,000 that are repaid within 16 days and 6 months","Loans of between $500 and $1,500 that are repaid in one-year terms","Loans of up to $3,000 that are repaid in terms of up to six months"]},{"niche":"personal loans","question":"What is a standard repayment period for a variable rate personal loan?","answers":["Between one and seven years","Between one and five years","Between 16 days and two years","Between 6 months and seven years"]},{"niche":"personal loans","question":"Can you make extra repayments on a variable rate loan?","answers":["Yes, but only with some lenders","No.","Only fixed rate personal loans offer this feature","You can make repayments up to a certain limit. "]},{"niche":"personal loans","question":"How quickly can you receive a loan after approval?","answers":["Some lenders can have it to you within the hour.","Within seven minutes.","It takes two hours to transfer funds between banks. ","One business day. "]},{"niche":"personal loans","question":"What is peer-to-peer lending?","answers":["A new lending platform that allows investors to lend to approved borrowers. ","Asking for money from your friends and family.","Taking out a personal loan with a friend as a guarantor.","Borrowing money from two different banks that are partners."]},{"niche":"personal loans","question":"Can temporary residents take out personal loans?","answers":["Yes, but there are restrictions set by lenders.","No, as they may leave the country before they've repaid the loan. ","Yes, they are able to access all the same financial products as permanent residents and citizens. ","No, this is not allowed by the Australian government. "]},{"niche":"personal loans","question":"Can you buy a motorbike with a car loan?","answers":["Yes, some lenders allow you to finance a range of motor vehicles. ","No, it's called a 'car loan' for a reason. ","Only by paying an extra fee is this possible. ","Yes this is possible with every lender. "]},{"niche":"personal loans","question":"What's the animal that stars in the Nimble TV ads? ","answers":["A bunny","A frog","A goat","A cat"]},{"niche":"personal loans","question":"Is a line of credit different to a home loan?","answers":["Yes","No","Maybe","It is a credit card"]},{"niche":"personal loans","question":"How much do I need to earn to get a personal loan?","answers":["It varies for every lender.","$20,000 p.a.","$50,000 p.a.","$35,000 p.a."]},{"niche":"personal loans","question":"Can you get a personal loan loan if you have bad credit?","answers":["Yes.","No. You are automatically rejected if you have any negative marks on your file ","Yes, but you need to pay additional money to set up the loan. ","Yes, but only with 'no credit check' lenders."]},{"niche":"personal loans","question":"Can you repay a payday loan early?","answers":["Yes. ","No, you have to repay it according to the terms set out in your contract. ","Yes, but you have to pay a fee. ","Yes but you have to physically visit the lender and pay in cash. "]},{"niche":"personal loans","question":"Can you take out a personal loan if you're on Centrelink. ","answers":["Yes. ","No, the government doesn't allow it. ","Yes but you have to apply for the loan through Centrelink.","Yes but you have to repay the loan within one month. "]},{"niche":"personal loans","question":"Can I earn rewards points for any personal loans?","answers":["Yes","No, this is illegal as it encourages people to get into debt. ","No, there are no lenders who currently offer this. ","Yes, but you have to borrow a minimum of $50,0000. "]},{"niche":"personal loans","question":"Can only payday lenders get a loan to you within one business day?","answers":["No, some banks can also offer this for their standard personal loans. ","Yes, only payday lenders have this technology.","No, every lender is able to do this. ","Yes, because they are transferring smaller loan amounts. "]},{"niche":"personal loans","question":"Can you only secure a personal loan with a car or a house?","answers":["No, you can use other items such as jewellery. ","Yes, only these two items are allowed. ","No, you can use any items whose total value equals the loan amount. ","Yes, as these assets never change in value no matter how long you hold them. "]},{"niche":"credit cards","question":"The Woolworths Money Everyday Platinum Credit Card earns what type of rewards points?","answers":["Everyday Money Reward Points","Qantas Points","Malaysia Airlines Enrich Miles",""]},{"niche":"credit cards","question":"What are two credit card providers let you balance transfer other types of credit accounts?","answers":["Virgin Money and Citibank","Citibank and CommBank","Westpac and Commbank","No providers let you do this. "]},{"niche":"credit cards","question":"At the end of the introductory period, a promotional balance transfer rate will revert to:","answers":["It differs for each provider, but is generally the cash advance rate or purchase rate. ","The cash advance rate","The purchase rate","You'll be charged the average of the cash advance rate and the purchase rate"]},{"niche":"credit cards","question":"Do you have to make repayments on a 0% balance transfer credit card before the introductory period is over?","answers":["Yes, you're required to make minimum monthly repayments.","No, not until the introductory period ends. ","No, but when the period ends you have to repay your entire balance.","Yes, your balance transfer amount is divided to ensure you repay the entire amount in the introductory period."]},{"niche":"credit cards","question":"Secured credit cards are offered by which Australian card provider?","answers":["None of the above","American Express","Coles ","ME Bank"]},{"niche":"credit cards","question":"Complimentary travel insurance is usually only offered on what type of credit card?","answers":["Platinum credit cards","Student credit cards","Basic credit cards","MoneyBank credit cards"]},{"niche":"credit cards","question":"The cheapest fee you'll pay per foreign transaction with an Australian credit card is","answers":["$0","$2.50","$10","1% of the transaction"]},{"niche":"credit cards","question":"The 28 Degrees Platinum MasterCard is best known for:","answers":["Charging no currency conversion fees or international transaction fees","Charging no annual fee","Always being 28 degrees to the touch","Having a complimentary concierge available 24/7"]},{"niche":"credit cards","question":"The Altitude Black card is offered by which card provider?","answers":["Westpac","RAMS","American Express","Woolworths Money"]},{"niche":"credit cards","question":"In the American Express Membership Ascent Rewards program, one Membership Reward Point can be exchange for: ","answers":["1 Qantas Frequent Flyer Point","1.25 Virgin Velocity Points","1 Air New Zealand Airpoints Dollar","One hot meal"]},{"niche":"credit cards","question":"Can you balance transfer a personal loan onto a credit card?","answers":["Yes","No","Yes but only for certain amounts","No, this is illegal."]},{"niche":"credit cards","question":"What is a credit score?","answers":["A three-digit number that summarises how well a person has managed their credit and debt.","A score that helps determine your employment history.","A three-digit number that estimates your equity.","A score that determines your current genuine savings."]},{"niche":"credit cards","question":"Can you use the complimentary travel insurance on a credit card as an additional cardholder?","answers":["Yes, but only with some providers.","No, it is only available for the main account-holder.","Yes, but you have to be travelling with the main cardholder. ","Yes, but you have different minimum spend requirements to meet in order to activate the cover. "]},{"niche":"credit cards","question":"What is a dual card account?","answers":["A card account that gives you two cards linked to the one account. ","A card that lets you have supplementary cardholders.","A card that gives you a spare card in case you lose yours. ","A card that can be broken in two for easy carrying. "]},{"niche":"credit cards","question":"In Australia, 0% balance transfer for life credit cards are offered by which institution?","answers":["None of the above","NAB","Commonwealth Bank","American Express"]},{"niche":"credit cards","question":"The Westpac Low Rate card currently has a purchase rate of:","answers":["13.49%","12.49%","10.49%","19.48%"]},{"niche":"credit cards","question":"The American Express Platinum Card is what type of card?","answers":["A platinum charge card","A platinum credit card","A standard charge card","A student charge card"]},{"niche":"credit cards","question":"The most prestiguous American Express card is called the?","answers":["Centurion","Centaurian","Celestian","Patriot"]},{"niche":"credit cards","question":"Complimentary credit card travel insurance usually covers claims caused by the following?","answers":["Hijacking","Civil unrest","Terrorism","HIV/AIDS"]},{"niche":"credit cards","question":"The ability to directly earn Emirates Skywards Miles is offered by which Australian credit card provider?","answers":["Citibank","American Express","ANZ","Commonwealth Bank"]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"How long can you be covered for life insurance?","answers":["Terms of up to 30 years.","Terms of up to 50 years.","Any time period in ten-year increments. ","All cover needs to be taken out for 20 years only. "]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"What does TPD stand for?","answers":["Total and Permanent Disability","Total and Permanent Distress","The Prime Dependants","The Permanent Disablement"]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"Only dogs and cats can be covered by pet insurance","answers":["No, a variety of pets can be covered. ","Yes, otherwise the insurance would get too complicated. ","Any animal that you keep in your house can be covered.","Yes they're the only ones that are legally allowed to be covered. "]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"What is a cooling off period?","answers":["Time given to let you back out of a policy. ","The first year of any policy where there are certain exclusions. ","A one-month period where a lender can investigate whether your lifestyle claims are accurate. ","Referring to when a policy is taken out in winter. "]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"How are funeral insurance premiums calculated?","answers":["A combination of your age and your determined risk factors. ","By your age.","By your gender and age. ","They change every quarter depending on a detailed survey you fill out. "]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"Does your occupation affect the level of premiums you pay for income protection?","answers":["Yes. The level of risk associated with an occupation will affect the premiums. ","No, this would be unfair to those in certain industries. ","Yes, but it only affects your premiums for the first year.","Yes, the premiums are set on a tiered scale. "]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"What happens to your super fund life insurance when you die?","answers":["The super fund trustee will decide how it's distributed. ","Your wishes need to be set out in your will. ","Your funds are absorbed by the super fund. ","Your funds are given to your next immediate family member. "]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"Select the pre-existing condition covered my travel insurance?","answers":["High cholestorel ","Heart disease","Chronic lung disease","Alcohol addiction"]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"Can you take out travel insurance if you're already overseas?","answers":["Yes, but a waiting period usually applies.","No, this is never possible.","Yes, but for much higher premiums.","Yes, but only for certain countries. "]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"Can you take out a trauma protection policy if you're under 18 years old?","answers":["Yes, you can be 17. ","No, you have to be 18. ","No, you have to be 21. ","There is no age limit. "]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"What is the insured's 'duty of disclosure'?","answers":["That they have to truthfuly answer questions asked by the insurer. ","You have to disclose all personal details of an insured event when you make a claim.","You have to tell the insurer if you're making a fraudulant claim. ","You have to tell your lawyer if you've made a fraudulant insurance claim in the past. "]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"How long would I have to quit smoking for to be considered a non-smoker?","answers":["At least 12 months","At least 3 months","At least four weeks","You can't ever have smoked "]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"Can you take out TPD insurance if you don't have a job?","answers":["Yes, you can be covered if you are a homemaker. ","No, this is not possible in any circumstance. ","Yes but you need to be volunteering at least four hours a week. ","Yes but you need to have dependant children. "]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"What is Needlestick Injury Benefit?","answers":["Cover if you become infected as a result of needlestick injury while working. ","Income protection cover for needlestick injury workers.","A benefit specific to needlestick injuries that occur while travelling. ","A generic term for cover when you're permanently disabled by any sharp object. "]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"Are specific countries excluded in travel insurance policies?","answers":["Yes, countries you won't be covered for countries you're advised to travel against by DFAT.","Specific countries aren't excluded, but you won't be covered for dangerous events that may take place in those countries. ","Yes there is a specific list you can check on the providers site.","There is a set list of countries insurers can't provide cover for."]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"Is TPD tax-deductibe?","answers":["Yes","No.","Yes, but only partially. ","No because it isn't classified as a business expense. "]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"Which of these is a common pet insurance exclusion?","answers":["Organ transplant surgery","Emergency pet boarding","Euthanasia ","Pet overseas travel insurance"]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"What is Key Person Insurance?","answers":["When a business insures themselves against the loss of key personell. ","When the breadwinner insures themselves against the loss of their income.","When the owner of a house takes out home and contents insurance. ","When you take out insurance in case you lose your keys. "]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"What is a buy-back benefit in trauma insurance?","answers":["This lets you repurchase life insurance (if you've linked your cover) after you've claimed. ","This lets you purchase two covers for the price of one.","If you cancel your cover you can buy it again without a waiting period.","You can purchase extras after you claim for a set price. "]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"What is a stepped premium for life insurance?","answers":["Premiums that increases as you get older.","Premiums that increases as your pay level increases.","Premiums that have thresholds that you need to meet in order to be eligible for discounts.","Premiums that are available for those in middle management. "]},{"niche":"insurance","question":"What does a car insuranbce policy that has a higher excess mean?","answers":["Lower premiums.","More extras.","Lower premiums and less extras. ","Higher premiums but more extras. "]}]
